### Meshkatul Anwer

# ABOUT

Software and System development bring me joy and hard problems motivate me most. I am fluent in java and JavaScript languages. I have worked with the large code base and have experiences with a object-oriented design with a strong focus on design, security and software reuse. My goal is to program well and build secure cloud scale systems.

Languages: Java, Javascript, Python, Typescript, SQL, shell, Go Technologies: Spring, kubernates, AWS, Azure, Terraform, docker, React, Angular, Kafka, Messaging, WebRTC

#### EXPERIENCE

• Bosch IO
Senior DevOps Engineer

Feb 2019 - Present

Waiblingen, Stuttgart

o Bosch Iothub: Working as a devops engineer for the Bosch IOT-HUB as part of Bosch Iot suite. Core responsibilities are as following. - keep the system up( High Available kubernetes based deployments) and secure 24hr (aws, kubernetes). - deploy the eclipse hono (open source based on vertx, spring-boot based java application) for the commercial use. - scale up the system to support millions of concurrent iot device connection. - implement new feature and extend to support different protocol adapters (MQTT, AMQP, COAP, HTTP, WEBSOCKET, LWM2M etc). - improve the microservice architecture for scalability, security and extensibility. - operate multi node kubernetes cluster and network optimization (load balancer, TLS termination etc). - maintain and tune the AMQP messaging service. - contribute to the bugfix effort and system-tests

### HSE24 Home Shopping Europe GmbH

Ismaning, Munich

Full Stack Developer

April 2018 - Jan 2019

Online Shop: Worked as Java developer for the old and new web shop. Played important part in integration of
payment provider to make the site PCI compliance. Extend the shop from end to end for different countries.
 Technologies used: Java, JavaScript, Spring frameworks, OSGI, karaf etc

#### MediaMarktSaturn

Central, Munich

Full Stack Developer Sept 2017 - April 2018

o Online Shop: Implementing Micro services related to the online shop as a java developer. Contributed to the development of new checkout services for the multichannel web-shop (refactoring monolithic IBW-WCS based online shop into smaller high-performance, highly available micro-services). Working with following technology and tools: - Modern Java (lambda, streams, rx-java, gradle, ant, maven),- Spring (reactive-core, webflux, data, security, mvc, jms, ws, boot, cloud), -Javascript (react, react server-side -rendering, node, gulp, webpack) - Docker, Rancher, Consul, Vagrant, Vault,- Api design(rest, web-services, open api specification)

### European Computer Telecoms AG

Centarl, Munich

Software Engineer

Dec 2011 - August 2017

- Next Generation call center solution: The new product for the company. This is the next generation of the communication system for the enterprise. The product is to support real-time communication with telephony integration. The technology stack used for the backend: java, spring, cometd, jetty, and for the frontend :javascript, webrtc, angularjs, react, webrtc
- ECT's service creation environment: I worked on ECT's service creation environment (complex browser based application) which empowers our customers to develop workflows for complex phone/voice, SMS and e-mail services and use the lower layer of standard IT and telecommunications protocols without specialist knowledge quickly and easily. My task to work with frontend development (GWT + java-script) and backend development: Java, jetty, jersey, RESTful API design and implementation, spring data. Along with coding I also provide consultancy for continues integration process.

# Cycos AG

Alsdorf, Aachen

Junior Software developer

May 2011 - Oct 2011

• Siemens Openscape: Main responsibility is to improve the web front end of Openscap Webclient by incorporating the modern web technologies. Other responsibilities include implementing new features and error correction. Working with technologies like java, jquery, XML/XSL, HTML, and JavaScript/AJAX.

# Ericsson Euro Lab

Student Researcher

Kreisfreie Stadt Aachen, Germany April 2010 - April 2011

 Service Creation Environment: - Participated with the research team at Euro Lab Aachen working on a novel Service Creation Environment for community services based on popular service technologies such as Web 2.0 (AJAX, REST, SOAP), communication services (SIP, IMS) and social -v networks. Java, EJB, AspectJ, GWT were the main technology used.

### Motorola Telecommunication

NOC Engineer (Software Development)

Dhaka, Bangladesh June 2007 - August 2009

• Unified Monitoring System: Research and Development of Telecom Network Management Software Application using JAVA technology (EJB, Servlets, JSP, AJAX, XML, Web Services , gwt, jquery, prototype, Google MAP Api etc)

#### **EDUCATION**

# Rheinisch-Westfälische Technische Hochschule Aachen

Software System Engineering

Aachen, Germany

Jan 2010 - April 2011

Military Institute of Science and Technology (MIST)

Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science and Engineering

Dhaka, Bangladesh Feb 2002 - Feb 2006

### LANGUAGES

• English: Fluent

• German: B1

• Bangla: First language